Guide to the World War II Pamphlet Collection 1937-1991 (bulk 1939-1945)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- United Nations - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1943; Inter-allied Review: A Monthly Résumé of Documents Relating to the Allied Struggle for Freedom. New York: United Nations Information Office, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 17/9)
- United Nations - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1944; The United Nations in Films: A List of 16 and 35 mm Motion Picture Films on the United Nations and Where They Can Be Secured. New York: United Nations Information Office, 1944. (Box 17/10)
- United States - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1940-1948; Germany's New Degradation. New York, 1940. (Caption title: "Reprinted from the New York Herald Tribune, July 27, 1940."); Hechinger, Fred M. Report on a Remnant of Nazi Victims: The Jews of Germany. Supplement: Germany's Nazi Legacies. New York: American Institute of International Information, 1948. (Box 17/11)
- United States - Domestic Politics: Censorship (in English), 1943; Code of Wartime Practices for American Broadcasters. Washington: U.S. Govt. Printing Office, 1943. (Publication prepared by the United States Government Office of Censorship.); Code of Wartime Practices for the American Press. Washington: U.S. Govt. Printing Office, 1943. (Publication prepared by the United States Government Office of Censorship.) (Box 17/12)
- United States - Domestic Politics: Wages (in English), undated; What Has Happened to Prices in Two Wars. n.d. (OS 23/4)
- United States - Foreign Relations: with North & South America (in Spanish), 1943; En Guardia: Suplemento - Conferencia de Comisiones de Fomento Interamericano. Washington, D.C.: Oficina del Coordinador de Asuntos Interamericanos, 1943. (A serial publication published by the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; only one issue available.) (Box 17/13)
- United States - Foreign Relations: with Poland (in English), 1942; Constitution of Poland: Proceedings in the House of Representatives and the Senate of the United States, April 30 and May 4, 1942. Washington, D.C: U.S.G.O.P, 1942. (Box 17/14)
- United States - Foreign Relations: with Serbians (in English), 1945; Congressional Record, Proceedings and Debates of the 79th Congress, First Session: Gerneral Mihailovich's Appeal to be Placed under the Allied Command. 1945.; Congressional Record, Proceedings and Debates of the 79th Congress, First Session: The Unanimous and Energetic Voice of the American Serbs--An Appeal for the Salvation of Democracy and the Heroic Serbian People in Yugoslavia. 1945. (Box 17/15)
- United States - Foreign Relations: with the United Nations (in English), 1943 and undated; The United Nations Study Kit. New York: United Nations Information Office, n.d. (Prepared by the United Nations Information Office in co-operation with the United States Office of Education.); The Thousand Million: Brief Stories About the United Nations, Where One Thousand Million Friends of the United States Live, Work, and Fight. Washington, D.C: Office of War Information, 1943. ("This pamphlet has been prepared by the staff of the Office of War Information to provide background material on the 28 United Nations at war, with the United States, against the Axis." verso quote) (Box 17/16)
- United States - News Coverage: "The American Hebrew" (in English), 1946; The American Hebrew. New York: American Hebrew, 1946. (Box 17/17)
- United States - News Coverage: "The American Hebrew" (in English), 1947; The American Hebrew. New York: American Hebrew, 1947. (Box 17/18)
- United States - News Coverage: Japan (in English), 1966; New Pearl Harbor Facts! Full Story: How U.S. Got Jap Secrets. Chicago, IL: Chicago Tribune, Special supplement, 1966. (Box OS 23/5)
- United States - News Coverage: Korea (in English), 1946-1947; Soviet Stymies Korean Independence. Washington D.C.: The Sunday Star, 1946. (Single page of "The Sunday Star".); [Miscellaneous news articles.] 1947. (sheet of photocopied articles from periodicals such as the "New York Times","New York Herald Tribune", "The Evening Star", etc.) (Box OS 23/6)
- United States - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1939; Rauschning, Hermann Hitler Could Not Stop. 1939. (Reprinted from "Foreign Affairs", an American quarterly review.) (Box 17/19)
- United States - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1940; Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies. Stop Hitler Now! Fort Benton, MT: The River Press, 1940. (This advertisement appeared in newspapers all over the U.S.) (Box OS 23/7)
- United States - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1942; Menne, Bernhard. German Industry on the Warpath. London: Hutchinson & Co., 1942. (Although published in London, Fight for Freedom Publications was part of an American advocacy organization dedicated to promoting U.S. involvement in WW2.); Lehmann-Russbueldt, Otto. Aggression: The Origin of Germany's War Machine. London: Hutchinson & Co., 1942. (Although published in London, Fight for Freedom Publications was part of an American advocacy organization dedicated to promoting U.S. involvement in WW2.); Menne, Bernhard, Heinrich Brüning, and Edward FitzGerald. The Case of Dr. Bruening. London: Hutchinson & Co., 1942. (Although published in London, Fight for Freedom Publications was part of an American advocacy organization dedicated to promoting U.S. involvement in WW2.); Geyer, Curt, Walter Loeb, and Edward FitzGerald. Gollancz in German Wonderland. London: Hutchinson & Co., 1942. (Although published in London, Fight for Freedom Publications was part of an American advocacy organization dedicated to promoting U.S. involvement in WW2.) (Box 17/20)
- United States - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1943; Koegler, Franz, and Edward FitzGerald. Oppressed Minority? London: Hutchinson & Co., 1943. (Although published in London, Fight for Freedom Publications was part of an American advocacy organization dedicated to promoting U.S. involvement in WW2.) (Box 17/21)
- United States - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1944; Poznański, Czeslaw. The Flaming Border. London: Hutchinson & Co., 1944. (Although published in London, Fight for Freedom Publications was part of an American advocacy organization dedicated to promoting U.S. involvement in WW2.); Uhlíř, František. Prague and Berlin, 1918-1938. London: Hutchinson & Co., 1944. (Although published in London, Fight for Freedom Publications was part of an American advocacy organization dedicated to promoting U.S. involvement in WW2.) (Box 18/1)
- United States - Propaganda: Against Japan (in English), 1943-1945; Jenkinson, Anthony. Know Your Enemy, Japan! New York: American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1943.; What Shall Be Done About Japan After Victory? Madison: American Historical Association, 1945. (prepared for the United States Armed Forces); Cant, Gilbert. War on Japan. New York: American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1945. (two copies) (18/2)
- United States - Propaganda: Against Japan (in English), 1944; Japan. New York: Overseas Editions, 1944. (Published as part of the April, 1944, issue of "Fortune Magazine"; entire issue not available.) (Box OS 19/6)
- United State - Propaganda: Analysis of (in English), undated; A Study of German Propaganda Being Spread in the United States. n.d. (This report references "News from Germany" in Box 3, Folder 16 and "Cartoons: Supplement to 'News from Germany'" located in Box 3, Folder 15.) (Box 18/3)
- United States - Propaganda: Combatting Anti-Semitism (in English), 1939-1945; Boorstin, Daniel J., George Mayberry, and John Rackliffe. Anti-semitism, a Threat to Democracy. Wakefield, Mass: Theodore DeLuca [distributor], 1939. (response to Father Charles E. Coughlin's anti-Semitic radio broadcasts); Sherman, Charles B. Labor's Enemy: Anti-Semitism. New York: Pamphlet Press, 1945.; The Answer to Anti-Semitism. New York: American League to Combat Anti-Semitism, Inc, 1939. (Box 18/4)
- United States - Propaganda: Communism Argument (in English), 1941 and undated; Foster, William Z. Communism versus Fascism. New York: Workers Library Publishers, 1941.; Education and the War: The Communists Speak for Themselves. New York: Young Communist League, n.d.; A People's Program of Struggle for the Defeat of Hitler and Hitlerism. San Francisco: State Committees of the Communist Party and the Young Comunist League of California, n.d.; The Meaning of the German-Soviet War. San Francisco: California State Committee, Communist Party, 1941. (Box 18/5)
- United States - Propaganda: Neutrality/Non-Interventionist Argument (in English), 1939-1941 and undated; How We Can Stay Neutral! the Deadly Parallel by C. Hartley Grattan. Washington, D.C.: National Committee to Keep America out of Foreign Wars, n.d.; Will the Arms Embargo Help Keep America Out of War? Washington, D.C.: National Committee to Keep America Out of Foreign Wars, n.d.; World Alliance News Letter. New York: World Alliance for International Friendship through the Churches (American Council) and Church Peace Union, 1939. (A serial publication; only one issue available.); [Letter to a Fellow American.] Washington, D.C.: National Committee to Keep America Out of Foreign Wars, n.d.; Fish, Hamilton. Keep America Out of Foreign Wars: Radio Address of Hon. Hamilton Fish of New York Over the National Broadcasting Co., April 21, 1939. Washington, D.C.: G.P.O, 1939.; Change in Neutrality Act Seen [as] Violation of International Law: Syracuse Attorney Cites British Protest Made during World War. Associated Press, n.d. (This newspaper clipping is part of a packet which include the two titles listed below.); Bryan, W.J. The Secretary of State to the German Ambassador (Bernstorff) No. 1379, File No. 763.72111/1930 (From "Foreign Relations of the United States", 1915, Supplement). n.d.; Wilmoth, William F. American Peace and Neutrality and Foreign Wars. Washington, D.C., n.d.; "I Hate War," said Franklin Delano Roosevelt and 83% of the American People are against War. Chicago: America First Committee, 1941.; Lindbergh, Charles A. Lindbergh's Message: An Address Delivered by Col. Charles A. Lindbergh at Manhattan Center Rally, April 23, 1941. New York: America First Committee, 1941.; Lindbergh, Charles A. Address by Charles A. Lindbergh, Minneapolis, MN, May 10, 1941. New York: America First Committee, 1941.; Lindbergh, Charles A. Address by Charles A. Lindbergh, Madison Square Garden, New York City, May 23, 1941. New York: America First Committee, 1941.; A Statement to the American People by Honorable Herbert Hoover, New York, May 11, 1941, upon the Immediate Relation of the United States to this War. 1941. (Box 18/6)
- United States - Propaganda: News Coverage (in English), 1942; The People vs. the Chicago Tribune. Chicago: Union for Democratic Action, 1942. (18/7)
- United States - Propaganda: Pearl Harbor (in English), 1944; Flynn, John T. The Truth About Pearl Harbor. New York: J.T. Flynn, 1944. (18/8)
- United States - Propaganda: Polish-Soviet Relations (in English), 1944-1945; Chamberlin, William H. Will Stalin Dictate an Eastern Munich? New York, 1944. (Reprinted from the American Mercury for March, 1944.); Cardwell, Ann S. Poland, Here Is the Record: An American's View [with a Foreword by William H. Chamberlin]. Ann Arbor, Mich: Michigan Committee of Americans for Poland, 1945. (Box 18/9)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for China (in English), 1944; Stewart, Maxwell S. War-time China. New York: American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1944. (18/10)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for Great Britain (in English), 1940-1943; Twelve O'clock. Reprint of Leading Editorial. New York: The New York Times, 1940. (This editorial is referenced in the pamphlet "We Shall Prevail" in Box 8, Folder 1); Goodhart, Arthur L. The British Constitution, a Description of the Relationships of the British Parliament, Privy Council and the Crown. New York: British information Services, 1943. (Box 18/11)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for Great Britain (in English), 1942; American Outpost in Great Britain. The Outpost, Published by the Americans in Britain. London, 1942. (Issued by the American Outpost in Great Britain; called Americans-in-Britain Outpost of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies.) (Box 18/12)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for Great Britain (in English), 1943; American Outpost in Great Britain. The Outpost, Published by the Americans in Britain. London, 1943. (Issued by the American Outpost in Great Britain; called Americans-in-Britain Outpost of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies.) (Box 18/13)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for Great Britain (in English), 1944; American Outpost in Great Britain. The Outpost, Published by the Americans in Britain. London, 1944. (Issued by the American Outpost in Great Britain; called Americans-in-Britain Outpost of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies.) (Box 18/14)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for Great Britain (in English), 1945; American Outpost in Great Britain. The Outpost, Published by the Americans in Britain. London, 1945. (Issued by the American Outpost in Great Britain; called Americans-in-Britain Outpost of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies.) (Box 18/15)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for India (in English), 1943; Farley, Miriam S. Speaking of India: 150 Questions and Answers. New York: American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1943. (18/16)
- United States - Propaganda: Support for Poland (in English), undated; [Advertisement praising Joseph Auslander's "An Open Letter to the Unconquerable Poles"]. undated. (This advertisement notes when and in which publications Joseph Auslanger's "An Open Letter..." will appear.) (Box OS 23/8)
- United States - Propaganda, Patriotic (in English), 1949; Our Economic System: What Is It? Indianapolis, IN: American Legion, National Americanism Commission, 1949.; Thru the Ages: [Man's Struggle for Liberty Has Not Been in Vain]. Indianapolis, IN: American Legion, National Americanism Commission, 1949.; Medal of Honor: [Awarded to Six Heroes Called "Joe"]. Indianapolis, IN: American Legion, National Americanism Commission, 1949. (Box 18/17)
- United States - Propaganda, Patriotic (in English), 1942; United States. Office of War Information. To All Who Use Libraries. U.S. Government Printing Office, 1942. (Box OS 23/9)
- United States - Propaganda, Patriotic: Book Recommendations (in English), undated; "Paper Bullets" by Leo J. Margolin: A Book-of-the-Month Club Recommendation. n.d.; Forum of the Nations, edited by Will Schaber. New York: Frederick Ungar, n.d. (Box 18/18)
- United States - Propaganda, Patriotic: War Effort (in English), 1942; Make and Mend for Victory: Alterations, Make Over, Accessories, Mending and Darning. New York: Spool Cotton Co, 1942. (Box 18/19)
- United States - Propaganda, Post-war: Isolationism Argument (in English), 1951 and undated; National Republic Lettergram, No. 234. Washington, D.C: National Republic, n.d.; [Letter to Dear Fellow American from Dorothea E. Miller.] New York, 1951 (This letter is part of a small packet which includes two other documents, listed below.); ["Daily News" article, Friday March 16, 1951]. New York: News Syndicate Co., Inc., 1951.; What Americans Can Do: To prevent their sons and husbands being sent to Europe as a permanent garrison without specific consent of Congress. n.d. (Box 18/20)
- United States - Reconstruction: Economic Concerns (in English), undated; Knight, John S. What's the Matter with America? Knight Newspapers, Inc., n.d. (Box 18/21)
- United States - Reconstruction: International Affairs (in English), 1945; Foreign Policy Bulletin. New York, N.Y: Foreign Policy Association, 1945. (A serial publication; only two issues available.) (Box 18/22)
- Yugoslavia - Propaganda, Serbian: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1944; The American Serb. Chicago: s.n., 1944. (Box 18/23)